Harshit Sahu

hsahu77@gmail.com

+91-8840213727

Github Website LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a Project Lead at RSystems with over 10 years of experience in the IT Industry. I have extensive experience of 10 years in ReactJs, NextJs 14, Playwright, Svelte, SvelteKit, NodeJs, GraphQLand Prisma 2. Recently developed a component Library harsh-ui.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Key Skills: JavaScript, ReactJs, NextJs 14, Playwright, SvelteJs, SvelteKit, NodeJs, Webpack, Tailwind.

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Tools: Git, RESTAPIS, JIRA, Confluence, Heroku and Netlify.

WORK EXPERIENCE

RSystems (Oct 2022 – Present)

ProjectLead

ReactJs,SvelteJs.Expertise-MicroFrontend, ComponentLibrary using React and Svelte using storybook. Playwright for Automation testing.

Dizzion

Senior Developer

ReactJs, TailwindCSS, Rollup etc

It's a web based platform that enables user to create a system as per their need in cloud. It has multiple business users that can see data related to them such as reports, services status etc.

My role was to develop the component library for them so that they can utilise it different microFrontend where each microFrontend is developed using ReactJS and TailwindCSS. Playwright was used for automation testing.

RSystems (Oct 2022 – Present)

ProjectLead

ReactJs, TailwindCSS, ShadcnUI. Playwright for Automation testing.

ManuLife

Senior Developer

ReactJs, TailwindCSS, ShadCn

It's a web based platform that enables user to create a policy and view various operation of policy. It has multiple business users that can see data related to them such as policy creation date, expiration, nominee details etc.

My role was to develop the SPA application for them using ReactJS, TailwindCSS and ShadcnUI. Playwright was used for automation testing.

BigBinary (April 2021 – Sep2022)

Senior Software Engineer

ReactJs, NodeJs. Expertise-MicroFrontend, ComponentLibrary using React.

neetoWireframe (viaBigBinary)

Senior Developer

ReactJS, TailwindCSS

NeetoWirefame- Web allows you to generate low-fidelity mockups without having any experience of sketching and google-powerpoint. With just a drag and drop user can create their wireframes and share it to the respective team. Itlets you focus on structure, content and features that the client wants to add. It also helps you to get immediate and meaningful feedback.

My role was to develop the frontend using ReactJS and TailwindCSS.

neetoChangeLog (viaBigBinary)

Senior Developer

ReactJS, TailwindCSS

NeetoChangeLog let customers know what's new/comingsoon/fixes/improvement/announcements etc. without in-terrupting them and letting clients see how people feel about our features in real-time via reactions and feedback features. It helps customers to get connected with the feature client build. It has many features like team manage- ment, reports , add/delete/when to publish changelog etc.

My role was to develop the frontend using ReactJS and TailwindCSS.

Tata Consultancy Services (March 2014 – April 2021)

Information Technology Analyst

ReactJs, Svelte, NodeJs, Prisma 2, Gatsby, NodeJs and Flutter

Involved in coding the core functionalities as per Client requests.

- Involved in creating performance efficient pages for the client using Reactjs(Gatsby,NextJs).
- Involved in creating websites that are compatible in all the formats i.e Desktop,tablet,mobile.
- Involved in understanding and analyzing the business requirements
- Involved in unit testing and deployment of the coded modules.
- Successfully delivered deliverables under strict schedules and quality control.
- Provided complete offshore support to daily production tasks.
- Involved in providing Hot fixes for production blockers.
- Converted a complete subsystem to Java for performance enhancements.
- Versatile team player and individual contributor with strong analytical and problem solving skills.
- Projects developed by me to test the significance and scalability of technology are https://reactquizapp.netlify.com/ and https://sveltequizapp.netlify.com/.

PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Awarded as Best Trainer in ReactJs by Talent Group(TCS).
- Delivered 21 lectures within TCS on ReactJs, Svelte and Flutter.
- Rated as 'Outstanding Performer' (KUDOS) during ILPAhmedabad 2014-15.
- Awarded with Certificate of Appreciation for efficiently handling all the challenges in terms of requirement analysis, technical complexity and developing Touchstone more robust.
- Awarded as STAR OF THE MONTH for handling challenges during Campus Season.
- Awarded as BEST TEAM for immense support.

EDUCATION

Hindustan College of Science and Technology, Mathura (June 2009 – July 2014)

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science & Technology)